https://www.moderndrummer.com/privacy-policy/

Our website address is: https://www.moderndrummer.com
Modern Drummer Publications recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of information provided to us. Accordingly, we strive for compliance with all international, federal and state privacy laws and follow industry best practices in order to best serve our community. The following guidelines have been created to demonstrate our commitment to privacy. They apply to all of our publications, books, events, and properties.
Our location and contact information:
Privacy Matters
Modern Drummer Publications, Inc.
271 Route 46 West
Suite H-212
Fairfield, NJ 07004
Phone: 973-239-4140
Fax: 973-239-7139
Email: mdinfo@moderndrummer.com
What personal data we collect and why we collect it
When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.
An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
The information we collect is gathered from several sources, which include product subscriptions, purchases, contest entries, readers poll voting, or registrations, either from print or online forms; website message postings; and survey information and direct or indirect purchases via telephone, direct mail, email, or other electronic sources. From these sources we may collect postal addresses, email addresses, telephone numbers, and/or demographic information for those individuals that volunteer such information. For each visitor to our websites, our Web server automatically recognizes the visitor’s domain name and IP address only. No other identifiable information is collected unless volunteered. In addition, we collect aggregate information on what Web pages visitors visit.
Moderndrummer.com uses Google Analytics to measure page views and traffic. Google Analytics saves user’s IP Address for 26 months. If you enter any of our contests, you will need to enter your name, address, email address, and phone number. Unless you check the “Send me more information from” our sponsors or Modern Drummer, your information will not be shared or used again and entry will be deleted after 26 months. If you affirmatively check the “Send me more information from” sponsor and/or Modern Drummer, your name and email address will be saved to our mailing list on Constant Contact and/or Mail Chimp, (click links for their privacy policies) and shared with the sponsor of that contest for their marketing efforts. If you no longer which to receive emails from Modern Drummer or the sponsor, the emails will have an “unsubscribe” function within them that you can use to unsubscribe.
How We Use Collected Information
The information we collect is used to improve the content of our Web pages, to customize the content and layout of our pages for each individual visitor, and/or to notify visitors about updates to our website. As part of a subscription, purchase, and/or registration agreement, subscribers, purchasers, and registrants will be contacted by us through mail, email, and/or phone to communicate with them about their subscription, purchase, and/or registration. They will be contacted for renewal, requalification, surveys, updates concerning their account profile, and special offers related to their subscription, purchase, and/or registration. We also use the information to contact them for marketing purposes on behalf of other reputable organizations, but we never share or give away this collected information.
Standard Email Communications
If you have registered for our products and/or services, and have supplied an email address, you will receive emails pertaining to your subscription, purchase, and/or registration. These are sent to maintain your account with Modern Drummer Publications. You can opt out of receiving these types of emails by using the opt-out mechanism located within the received email message.
Marketing Email Communications
For marketing emails, we retain three types of usage permission for submitted email addresses as defined below. You can opt out of receiving marketing emails about Modern Drummer Publications products and from outside companies either in response to a received email or within this Privacy Policy.
1. Emails About Related Products and Services
If you volunteer an email address you may be contacted by us regarding other products, services, and/or upcoming events that are related to our magazine. If you do not wish to receive these types of e-mails from us, you can opt out of receiving these types of emails by using the opt-out mechanism located within the received email message.
2. Emails About Other Modern Drummer Products and Services
If you volunteer an email address you may be contacted by us regarding any other Modern Drummer Publications products, services, and/or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive these types of emails from us, please let us know by calling us at the above telephone number or writing to us at the above street address/email address. You can also opt out of receiving these types of emails by using the opt-out mechanism located within the received email message.
3. Emails From Outside Companies
If you volunteer an email address you may be contacted by carefully selected outside companies for reputable promotional purposes. If you do not wish to receive emails from other companies, please let us know by calling us at the above telephone number or writing to us at the above street address/email address. You can also opt out of receiving these types of emails by using the opt-out mechanism located within the received email message.
All Emails
If you wish to opt out of these three types of email marketing messages at once, please let us know by calling us at the above telephone number or writing to us at the above street address/email address.
It will take up to ten business days to process your email opt-out request. Please note that you may receive additional communications from us or an outside company after submitting your request if your email address was selected from our database just prior to receiving and processing your request.
Postal Communications
If you volunteer a postal address you may receive periodic mailings to relate information about new products, services, and/or upcoming events. We may also provide this information to other carefully selected outside companies for promotional purposes. If you do not wish to receive mailings from us or other companies, please let us know by calling us at the above telephone number or writing to us at the above street address/email address.
It will take up to three months to process your do-not-mail request. Please note that you may receive additional communications from us or other companies after submitting your request if your postal address was selected from our database just prior to receiving and processing your request.
Telephone Communications
If you volunteer a telephone number you may receive periodic telephone calls about new products, services, and/or upcoming events. We may also provide this information to carefully selected outside companies for promotional purposes. If you do not wish to receive telephone calls from us, please let us know by calling us at the above telephone number or writing to us at the above street address/email address.
It will take up to one month to process your do-not-call request. Please note that you may receive additional communications from us or other companies after submitting your request if your telephone number was selected from our database just prior to receiving and processing your request.
Fax Communications
If you volunteer a fax number you may receive promotional faxes on a very limited basis. Only those with whom we have an existing business relationship (such as an established subscription or registration) will receive such faxes. If you do not wish to receive such faxes, please let us know by calling us at the above telephone number or writing to us at the above street address/email address.
What rights you have over your data
If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Correcting/Updating Personal Information
Upon request, we offer individuals the ability to have inaccuracies corrected within their contact information. This information can be corrected by writing to us at the above address. Current subscribers and registrants can also access and change their information through our website by selecting the appropriate link on the website where their current subscription/registration resides.
Cookies
If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.
Links
This site may contain links to other websites in the form of hyperlinks. Modern Drummer Publications is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.
Security
Modern Drummer Publications takes every precaution to protect your information from unauthorized use. When you submit sensitive information via our websites, the information is protected both online and offline. When our registration/subscription form asks for a credit card number or other sensitive information, that information is encrypted and protected with the best encryption software in the industry—SSL.
Changes to Privacy Policy
We may use customer information for new, unanticipated uses not disclosed in this privacy notice. If our information practices change at some time in the future, we will post the policy changes to our website to notify you of them. If you are concerned about how your information is used please email us at mdinfo@moderndrummer.com.
Create a new list
